<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>job doc on bretsw</title>
    <link>http://bretsw.com/tags/job-doc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in job doc on bretsw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[CC BY-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bretsw.com/tags/job-doc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/diversity-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/diversity-statement/</guid>
      <description>In 2012, novelist John Scalzi wrote a blog post titled Straight White Male: The Lowest Difficulty Setting There Is. This description has resonated with me. It situates any difficulties I have had in a position relative to other experiences, stories, and identities that are generally, systemically more challenging. For instance, few would describe their experiences during the COVID-19 pandemic and American racism pandemic of 2020 as easy. It has been hard for anyone to be productive this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>Research Agenda I study online learning environments. I research networked learning at the intersection of educational psychology, instructional technology, and information science. My scholarship investigates the networked learning made possible by the novel social and environmental conditions afforded by the Internet. Specifically, I explore how social media platforms support online learning communities. In various projects, I have framed networked learning in terms of self-directed learning (i.e., an agentic perspective on socio-cognitive processes), affinity spaces (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/teaching-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/teaching-statement/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Philosophy My teaching philosophy is shaped by two primary principles. These principles are related to networked learning, a self-directed and social approach to learning. My first role as an educator is to affirm and strengthen students’ agency. I invite them to co-create their learning experiences, help them self-reflect, and guide them toward asking better questions. Second, I strive to model, and invite students to practice, the principles of open science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>