<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</title>
    <link>http://bretsw.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[CC BY-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bretsw.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Notes from EME6356: Learning &amp; Web Analytics</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/eme6356-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/eme6356-hub/</guid>
      <description>I wanted a place to compile all of my slide decks as I teach EME6356: Learning &amp;amp; Web Analytics at Florida State University. Enjoy!
Course Description This course addresses the collection and use of data for decision making and assessment in learning and human performance contexts. Students will get hands-on experience with small data sets and will learn how big data sets are collected and used. The course will explore the role that analytics plays in education and related fields, identify the types of questions that might be answered via both quantitative and qualitative analytics, and engage in analytic- related problem solving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Notes from EME6357: Evaluation of Instruction &amp; Training in Human-Performance Technology</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/eme6357-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/eme6357-hub/</guid>
      <description>I wanted a place to compile all of my slide decks as I teach EME6357: Evaluation of Instruction &amp;amp; Training in Human-Performance Technology at Florida State University. Enjoy!
Course Description This course focuses on the evaluation of training and instruction through a systemic analysis of the organization sponsoring the training program. The course also provides the knowledge and skills for conducting an HPT-based evaluation of training systems. Students actively participate in discussions, presentations, synthesis of materials, and the writing of papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper: Balancing open science and privacy in the context of learning analytics</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-balancing-open-science-and-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/new-paper-balancing-open-science-and-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Background I recently co-authored (with Josh Rosenberg a response to a valuable paper by Ifenthaler and Schumacher (2016) as a part of a special issue of Educational Technology Research &amp;amp; Development on &amp;ldquo;Shifting to Digital&amp;rdquo; in light of the COVID-19 pandemic.
Here is a succinct description of the aims of the special issue:
 This Special Issue is unique in that it will focus on multiple perspectives where respondent authors write about the implications of scholarship on addressing current challenges related to an increased focus of digital learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My AECT 2020 Work</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/aect-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/aect-2020/</guid>
      <description>Workshop - Simple Collection and Powerful Analysis of Twitter Data Using R Friday, October 30, 2020
The workshop website is accessible at https://bretsw.github.io/aect20-workshop/. From here, you can link to all workshop materials, including slides, RStudio Cloud workspace, and data.
Panel - Factors Influencing Doctoral Students’ Perseverance in Online Instructional Technology Programs Tuesday, November 3, 2020
The online doctoral student is a new phenomenon. This session brings together doctoral students to discuss their experiences persevering in fully online instructional technology programs at their own universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Inter-rater Reliability</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/irr-visual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/irr-visual/</guid>
      <description>Background on Reporting Inter-rater Reliability Qualitative studies often report inter-reliability (IRR) scores as a measure of the trustworthiness of coding, or an assurance to readers that they might follow the researcher&amp;rsquo;s codebook and expect to find similar results. How these scores get reported varies widely. Often, I see just the range of scores reported, hopefully with Cohen&amp;rsquo;s kappa calculated in addition to the more straightforward percent agreement. The kappa is important because it takes into account variance in the frequency of a code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Reflection</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/career-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/career-reflection/</guid>
      <description>I’ve applied for a handful of academic jobs in the past six months, as many tenure track faculty positions as I could imagine fitting my experiences and skills. In the present higher-education-during-COVID-19 reality, that has amounted to six jobs to apply to (with hopefully more posted in the coming weeks). Three of those I applied to have since been removed from consideration by university-wide hiring freezes.
Work is hard to come by nearly everywhere these days, giving me cause to pause and reflect on my professional journey to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/diversity-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/diversity-statement/</guid>
      <description>In Becoming Qualitative Researchers: An Introduction (2016), Corrine Glesne argued that to establish the trustworthiness of qualitative research, a researcher must reflect on their positionality, answering, “Why do I notice what I notice?” (p. 153).
I am writing this diversity statement as a white, cisgender, heterosexual, American-born man. My parents, grandparents, and great grandparents all received university degrees. It was always assumed that I would pursue an undergraduate degree, and my decisions to later pursue a Master’s degree and a Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>Research Agenda I study online learning environments. I research networked learning at the intersection of educational psychology, instructional technology, and information science. My scholarship investigates the networked learning made possible by the novel social and environmental conditions afforded by the Internet. Specifically, I explore how social media platforms support online learning communities. In various projects, I have framed networked learning in terms of self-directed learning (i.e., an agentic perspective on socio-cognitive processes), affinity spaces (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/teaching-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/teaching-statement/</guid>
      <description>Teaching Philosophy My teaching philosophy is shaped by two primary principles. These principles are related to networked learning, a self-directed and social approach to learning. My first role as an educator is to affirm and strengthen students’ agency. I invite them to co-create their learning experiences, help them self-reflect, and guide them toward asking better questions. Second, I strive to model, and invite students to practice, the principles of open science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Themes</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-themes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve wrapped up numerous cycles of qualitative coding of interview data for my dissertation, Into the edu-verse: New teachers seeking induction support on social media, I used geom_tile() in {ggplot2} to create heatmap plots to help me quickly visualize how thematic codes varied by interview participant.
Heatmap Comparison of Thematic Codes by Interview Participant Note. Columns have been computationally reordered using principle components analysis (PCA) so that side-by-side columns are more similar than non-adjacent columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparisons in Twitter #Edchat during COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/edchat-comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/edchat-comparisons/</guid>
      <description>I am in the midst of two projects looking at how Twitter #Edchat tweets may have been affected by the COVID-19 pandemic. The first project is primarily comparing tweets in Spring 2020 to those in the same timeframe a year earlier. The second project focuses on Spring 2020 but compares tweets from U.K. and U.S. users. I used geom_tile() in {ggplot2} to create heatmap plots to help me quickly visualize and compare a large number of data points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bret&#39;s Project Landscape (hosted on Trello)</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/trello-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/trello-projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects of Bret Staudt Willet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Proposal</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-proposal/</guid>
      <description>Into the Edu-verse: Early-Career Educators Seeking Induction Support on Social Media On November 26, 2019, I successfully defended my dissertation proposal for my PhD in Educational Psychology and Educational Technology through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Education. I have shared the full text of my proposal here: https://bretsw.github.io/dissertation-proposal-text/
You can scroll through my presentation slides for the defense below (use the arrow keys) or view them here.
 At the end of the defense, I asked my committee for advice on sustaining a project as large as the dissertation, and they offered some great wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content, Conversation, &amp; Context: How Educators Talk to Each Other in Twitter #Edchat</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/content_conversation_context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/content_conversation_context/</guid>
      <description>On November 11, 2019, I gave a talk on a recent research project as part of the Educational Psychology and Educational Technology (EPET) brownbag series at Michigan State University.
Abstract Despite potential benefits, conversations on Twitter are often hard to follow. Several factors contribute: the volume of new messages, the unruly mass of content, and the mashup of features that comprise the platform. For educators to participate in professional learning on Twitter, they must be able to find coherence in these conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AECT Graduate Student Assembly: Webinar Series</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/aect-gsa-webinars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/aect-gsa-webinars/</guid>
      <description> February 7, 2019: How to Review AECT International Convention Proposals   March 27, 2019: How to Become and Effective and Efficient Academic Writer   May 8, 2019: Navigating Leadership Opportunities in AECT   July 24, 2019: Information and Communications Technology for Enhancing Education Internationally   August 22, 2019: Design and Research Guidelines for Diverse Makerspaces   October 2, 2019: What Happens in Vegas Does Not Stay in Vegas   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursework: PhD in Educational Psychology and Educational Technology</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_epet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_epet/</guid>
      <description>I have completed the coursework for my Ph.D. in Educational Psychology and Educational Technology through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Education.
Course department guide:
* CEP = Department of Counseling, Educational Psychology, &amp;amp; Special Education
* TE = Department of Teacher Education
* WRA = Department of Writing, Rhetoric, &amp;amp; American Cultures
Theory and History CEP 900: Proseminar in Learning, Technology and Culture Summer 2016
Instructors: Dr. Cary Roseth, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Grandpas</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/tale-of-two-grandpas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/tale-of-two-grandpas/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passion Talks 2016: The Strength of the Weak Ties</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/passion_talks_strength_of_weak_ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/passion_talks_strength_of_weak_ties/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Strength of Weak Ties</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/strength_of_weak_ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/strength_of_weak_ties/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation Interview</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/motivation-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/motivation-interview/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>proCATstination</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/procatstination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/procatstination/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursework: Master of Arts in Educational Technology</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_maet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_maet/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, I completed a Master of Arts degree in Educational Technology through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Education. Here I offer a bit of my experience in each course.
The &amp;ldquo;CEP&amp;rdquo; before the course number stands for &amp;ldquo;Counseling, Educational Psychology, and Special Education,&amp;rdquo; the name of the department in the College of Education.&amp;rdquo;
CEP 800: Psychology of Learning in School and Other Settings Summer 2013
Instructors: Dr. Hannah Klautke, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/making/</guid>
      <description> Makerspaces   Repurposing   Maker Movement Assessment   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alessia&#39;s Bulwark</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/alessia_bulwark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/alessia_bulwark/</guid>
      <description>“Art is a lie that makes us realize truth.”
Picasso’s famous words were among those jumbling in my head while watching Super Bowl commercials this year. That’s right, my boyfriend was watching football; I was watching commercials. Anyway, Liam Neeson had me in stitches when he said, “BigBuffetBoy85, I’m coming for you, with lots of barbarians and dragons.” Hilarious for riffing off his Taken franchise persona to sell Clash of Clans to a new audience, but also, well, awkwardly, nervously funny because this made-up marketing scenario tapped into something deeper, something that hit me close to home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/testing/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Communities</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/online_communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/online_communities/</guid>
      <description> Perceiving Community   Patterning Community   Embodying Community   Modeling Community   Synthesizing Community   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursework: Graduate Certificate in Serious Game Design and Research</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_serious_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_serious_game/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I completed a 3-course Graduate Certificate in Serious Game Design and Research through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Communication Arts and Sciences. Here I offer a bit of my experience in each course.
The &amp;ldquo;TC&amp;rdquo; before the course number stands for &amp;ldquo;Telecommunications,&amp;rdquo; the old department name in the College of Communication Arts and Sciences before they changed it to &amp;ldquo;Media and Information.&amp;rdquo;
TC 831: Theories of Games and Interaction for Design Fall 2012</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Read Socially</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/learning-to-read-socially/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/learning-to-read-socially/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tell a Good Story</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/tell-a-good-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/tell-a-good-story/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>