<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social media on Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</title>
    <link>https://bretsw.com/tags/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social media on Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[CC BY-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bretsw.com/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Subreddits: Change and Continuity in Teaching-Related Online Spaces</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/publication/staudtwillet_carpenter_inpress-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/publication/staudtwillet_carpenter_inpress-copy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers on Reddit? Exploring Contributions and Interactions in Four Teaching-Related Subreddits</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/publication/staudtwillet_carpenter_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/publication/staudtwillet_carpenter_2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Multiple Learning Spaces Within a Single Teacher-Focused Twitter Hashtag</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/publication/greenhalgh_rosenberg_staudtwillet_koehler_akcaoglu_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/publication/greenhalgh_rosenberg_staudtwillet_koehler_akcaoglu_2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition Supports Through Social Media</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/project/transition-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/project/transition-support/</guid>
      <description>Introduction New teachers face numerous decisions as they transition from teacher preparation into enacting practice (i.e., their induction period). They must reconcile conflicting messages about what and how to teach from the academic world of the preparation program and the practical world of their school of employment. Interviews with new teachers provide evidence of why new teachers seek supports for professional leaning to complement formal induction programs offered by schools and districts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should Be the Role of Social Media in Education?</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/publication/greenhow_galvin_staudtwillet_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/publication/greenhow_galvin_staudtwillet_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting How and Why Educators Use Twitter: Tweet Types and Purposes in #Edchat</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/publication/staudtwillet_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/publication/staudtwillet_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching-Related Subreddits</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/project/teaching-subreddits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/project/teaching-subreddits/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Reddit is an understudied social media platform with a large and international base of users. Reddit has more than 430 million average monthly active users globally and 130,000 active discussion forums, called subreddits. Among these many subreddits, several are education-focused, including 16 that comprise the Reddit Education Network. However, Reddit’s potential for hosting teaching-related discussions has been the subject of relatively little research compared to other social media platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educational Twitter Hashtags</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/project/twitter-hashtags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/project/twitter-hashtags/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Studies of educational uses of Twitter have often noted the inclusion of hashtags (i.e., a key word or phrase preceded by the &amp;ldquo;#&amp;rdquo; symbol) in tweets to organize conversations. Educational Twitter hashtags may be used as a general topical index (e.g., #education) as well as a marker of planned discussions called Twitter chats (e.g., #Edchat, #michED), which occur both synchronously and asynchronously. These hashtags are used to create both formal and informal leanring spaces, and they may be considered an emergent type of online learning environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://bretsw.com/project/social-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretsw.com/project/social-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Social scholarship is a framework that takes into account how social media affect forms of scholarly activity including discovery and research, teaching and learning, integration, and application. Social scholarship continues to evolve in light of changing understandings in the field of educational technology and the role social media play in the academy. Recent examples of social scholarship include altmetrics, interdisciplinary projects, crowdsourced educational technology syllabi, and a reconsideration of the needs of research participants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>