<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>msu on bretsw</title>
    <link>http://bretsw.com/tags/msu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in msu on bretsw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[CC BY-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bretsw.com/tags/msu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Themes</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-themes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve wrapped up numerous cycles of qualitative coding of interview data for my dissertation, Into the edu-verse: New teachers’ agency in self-directed learning with social media, I used geom_tile() in {ggplot2} to create heatmap plots to help me quickly visualize how thematic codes varied by interview participant and by modality.
Codes by Participant Codes by Modality I&amp;rsquo;ve shared the code to produce these plots in a GitHub repository, and you can also view on RPubs a variety of different heatmaps I created en route to these final plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bret&#39;s Project Landscape (hosted on Trello)</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/trello-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/trello-projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects of Bret Staudt Willet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Proposal</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-proposal/</guid>
      <description>Into the Edu-verse: Early-Career Educators Seeking Induction Support on Social Media On November 26, 2019, I successfully defended my dissertation proposal for my PhD in Educational Psychology and Educational Technology through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Education. I have shared the full text of my proposal here: https://bretsw.github.io/dissertation-proposal-text/
You can scroll through my presentation slides for the defense below (use the arrow keys) or view them here.
 At the end of the defense, I asked my committee for advice on sustaining a project as large as the dissertation, and they offered some great wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>K. Bret Staudt Willet PhD Candidate, Michigan State University
Email - Twitter - Github - LinkedIn - Google Scholar
Keywords: networked learning, social media, educational technology
Download a PDF copy of my CV
Education Michigan State University PhD, Educational Psychology &amp;amp; Educational Technology (Expected October 2020)
 Dissertation: Into the edu-verse: New teachers’ agency in self-directed learning with social media Committee: Matthew Koehler, Christine Greenhow, Ralph Putnam, Gail Richmond Defended proposal: November 26, 2019  View slides Read proposal  Advanced to candidacy: February 3, 2019  MA, Educational Technology (2015)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursework: PhD in Educational Psychology and Educational Technology</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_epet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_epet/</guid>
      <description>I have completed the coursework for my Ph.D. in Educational Psychology and Educational Technology through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Education.
Course department guide:
* CEP = Department of Counseling, Educational Psychology, &amp;amp; Special Education
* TE = Department of Teacher Education
* WRA = Department of Writing, Rhetoric, &amp;amp; American Cultures
Theory and History CEP 900: Proseminar in Learning, Technology and Culture Summer 2016
Instructors: Dr. Cary Roseth, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursework: Master of Arts in Educational Technology</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_maet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_maet/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, I completed a Master of Arts degree in Educational Technology through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Education. Here I offer a bit of my experience in each course.
The &amp;ldquo;CEP&amp;rdquo; before the course number stands for &amp;ldquo;Counseling, Educational Psychology, and Special Education,&amp;rdquo; the name of the department in the College of Education.&amp;rdquo;
CEP 800: Psychology of Learning in School and Other Settings Summer 2013
Instructors: Dr. Hannah Klautke, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursework: Graduate Certificate in Serious Game Design and Research</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_serious_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/coursework_serious_game/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I completed a 3-course Graduate Certificate in Serious Game Design and Research through Michigan State University&amp;rsquo;s College of Communication Arts and Sciences. Here I offer a bit of my experience in each course.
The &amp;ldquo;TC&amp;rdquo; before the course number stands for &amp;ldquo;Telecommunications,&amp;rdquo; the old department name in the College of Communication Arts and Sciences before they changed it to &amp;ldquo;Media and Information.&amp;rdquo;
TC 831: Theories of Games and Interaction for Design Fall 2012</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>