<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</title>
    <link>http://bretsw.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Digital space of K. Bret Staudt Willet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[CC BY-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bretsw.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Inter-rater Reliability</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/irr-visual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/irr-visual/</guid>
      <description>Background on Reporting Inter-rater Reliability Qualitative studies often report inter-reliability (IRR) scores as a measure of the trustworthiness of coding, or an assurance to readers that they might follow the researcher&amp;rsquo;s codebook and expect to find similar results. How these scores get reported varies widely. Often, I see just the range of scores reported, hopefully with Cohen&amp;rsquo;s kappa calculated in addition to the more straightforward percent agreement. The kappa is important because it takes into account variance in the frequency of a code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Themes</title>
      <link>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bretsw.com/post/dissertation-themes/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve wrapped up numerous cycles of qualitative coding of interview data for my dissertation, Into the edu-verse: New teachers seeking induction support on social media, I used geom_tile() in {ggplot2} to create heatmap plots to help me quickly visualize how thematic codes varied by interview participant.
Heatmap Comparison of Thematic Codes by Interview Participant Note. Columns have been computationally reordered using principle components analysis (PCA) so that side-by-side columns are more similar than non-adjacent columns.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>